Welcome
test subjects
to another exploration of the anomalous
Today
we delve into SCP-008
also known as the "Zombie Plague"
SCP-008 is classified as Euclid
This complex prion is a Class V extreme biological hazard
stored in highly secure G2 sites
The containment protocols are stringent
ensuring incineration and irradiation measures are ready in case of any breach
The quarantine period for operatives leaving the facility is four months
In the event of a breach
all measures must be deployed to ensure the prion does not escape containment
Evacuation is not an option; complete eradication is the only policy
SCP-008 exhibits terrifying traits
100% infectiousness
100% lethality
and transmission through all bodily fluids and mucous membranes
However
it is not airborne or waterborne
Symptoms manifest within three hours
starting with flu-like symptoms and severe dementia
leading to coma and death within 20 hours
Test Log 008-Alpha
Initial tests on infected subjects revealed rapid onset of symptoms
with subjects exhibiting high fever
severe dementia
and eventual coma
Necrotic tissue displayed remarkable resilience
functioning despite extensive cellular damage
Test Log 008-Beta
Infected tissue samples showed increased oxygen storage in red blood cells
leading to slower blood flow and enhanced muscle endurance
Even after total organ failure
the nervous and muscular systems remained active for hours
Infected subjects exhibit erratic behavior
driven by basic instincts
They energetically move towards sights
sounds
and smells associated with living humans
attempting to ingest them upon contact
Neutralizing these subjects requires significant cranial trauma
Test Proposal 008-Gamma
Long-Term Survival Analysis
Hypothesis
SCP-008 infected subjects can survive for over ten years without nutrition
thanks to their drastically reduced metabolism
Understanding these mechanisms could provide insights into extending human survival in extreme conditions
Test Proposal 008-Delta
Behavioral Conditioning
Hypothesis
Despite severe cognitive damage
SCP-008 infected subjects may retain some capacity for conditioned behavior
This could lead to methods for controlling or redirecting their actions in containment scenarios
Test Proposal 008-Epsilon
Cross-Species Infection
Hypothesis
Cross-species analysis could reveal key differences in susceptibility and symptom progression
providing valuable data for understanding SCP-008's origins and potential weaknesses
Addendum 008-1
SCP-500
known for its remarkable healing properties
has been found to completely cure SCP-008 even in advanced stages
This discovery opens new avenues for treatment and containment strategies
The pursuit of understanding SCP-008 continues
Through rigorous experimentation
we aim to harness its potential and ensure its safe application
The science must continue
no matter the cost
Thank you for joining us in this journey of discovery
Remember to like
subscribe
and hit the notification bell for more explorations into the unknown
Until next time
stay vigilant
stay safe
and remember the science must continue